

# TRIPP

.NET DEVELOPER

# CONTACT

**PHONE** 717 462 2188

EMAIL calebtripp@outlook.com

# ONLINE

#### **Portfolio**

calebtripp.github.io

#### **GitHub**

github.com/calebtripp

### codewars

codewars.com/users/calebtripp

# **CURRENT READ**

The Clean Coder Uncle Bob

# LINKEDIN linkedin.com/in/calebtripp

#### SUMMARY

I'm a .NET developer currently focused on writing back end C# solutions. I have experience with querying a database, API integration, unit testing, debugging, and a good foundation in Object Oriented Programming which I utilize to create solutions to complex problems, implement new features and refactor existing code.

I am committed to writing readable and maintainable code that can rapidly adapt to changing business needs. I am familiar with product lifecycle, agile methodology, and am comfortable working solo or collaborating with teams to deliver quality product on

# TOOLS

- LANGUAGES: C#, SQL, JS, HTML, CSS
- FRAMEWORKS: .NET6, ASP.NET, MVC
- Git version control
- REST API Integration, JSON, Dapper DRM
- Visual Studio, VS Code, MYSQL

# **PROJECTS**

#### **PACKFORTHEWEATHER**

https://packfortheweather.azurewebsites.net MVC web app that returns a personalized outfit packing list based on user input for destination, trip duration and comfort preference. The app calls the forecast via API then generates a list of weather appropriate outfits to pack tailored to user comfort.

TOOLS: C#, API, Razor, ASP.Net CORE MVC, HTML, JS, CSS

## SWANSONREST

github.com/calebtripp/APIs-and-JSON-Exercise

A C# console app that uses public REST APIs to call and parse object and array responses into strings which are returned to simulate a conversation between Ron Swanson and Kanye West.

TOOLS: C#, REST APIs, JSON, NUGET PKG.

#### ORM-DAPPER

github.com/calebtripp/ORM-and-Dapper-Exercise

C# Console app using Dapper ORM to perform parameterized database query and modification via SQL and demonstrate use of inheritance through use of interface.

TOOLS: C#, SQL, JSON, Dapper ORM

### **TACOPARSER**

github.com/calebtripp/TacoParser

A C# console app which, given a CSV file containing taco bell locations in Alabama, parses through the file and finds the two locations which are farthest apart based on their latitude & longitude. The program is adaptable to different applications using locations.

TOOLS: C#, .NET, VERSION CONTROL, UNIT TESTS

# CERTIFICATION

LANGUAGE PROFICIENCY C#, SQL, JS, HTML, CSS

TrueCoders 11/2022

# EDUCATION

FULL STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEERING BOOTCAMP

TrueCoders 9/2022 - 11/2022

## **BACHELOR OF ARTS**

Valley Forge University 2008

# ACHIEVEMENTS

Implemented cloud based Kanban workflow achieving transparent, real time collaboration company wide. Wheel Worx | 2021

7771001 7701X | 2021

Successfully directed consumer market expansion.

Wheel Worx | 2019

Negotiated 30% net savings for East Coast Freight.

Experea Healthcare | 2016

Led OzLink software integration to automate shipping resulting in a 50% reduction in West Coast ship process time.

Experea Healthcare | 2015

Created quality control measures reducing shipping errors by 22%

Freestate Medical Supply | 2019

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

(CONTINUED)

#### GENERAL MANAGER / BUSINESS MANAGER

Wheel Worx, Inc. General Manager 1/2020 – 9/2022

Business Manager 7/2017- 1/2020

At Wheel Worx I led expansion into the consumer market, launching the first retail location in March 2019. Market growth was robust, and while managing the retail operation I worked to develop adjacent areas of the business and organize additional expansion opportunities.

Key responsibilities and accomplishments:

- Forecast and build scalable systems for projected growth.
- Assess processes, refine for efficiency and write technical documentation.
- Proactively plan and problem solve to optimize allocation of resources.
- Monitor key account workload, manage conflicts to reach quick resolution, ensure production deadlines and quality standards are achieved.
- Establish onboarding, training, and incentive programs to recruit and retain employees.
- Train and coach team members to facilitate good morale and boost productivity.
- Develop and execute successful marketing strategy, facilitate company rebranding.
- Assess business model, compile and present metrics and growth proposals to stakeholder.

#### DISTRIBUTION SUPERVISOR

10/2014 Freestate Medical Supply - 10/2015 Experea Healthcare - 7/2016 - ABC Medical - 6/2017

At Freestate / Experea / ABC, distribution transitioned from VA to PA, and we deployed the PA distribution center from scratch. Around the merger with Experea Healthcare I assumed full responsibility of East Coast distribution while volume doubled. I collaborated nationwide to maximize efficiency, successfully leading through another doubling merger with ABC Medical.

Key responsibilities and accomplishments:

- Sole oversight of East Coast distribution, ensuring critical delivery of medical supplies.
- Maintain compliance with state and national regulatory agencies.
- Author comprehensive technical manual establishing best practices for 7 positions.
- Develop quota resulting in accurate productivity gauging and efficiency control.
- Collaborate with colleagues to proactively manage inventory and minimize shrinkage.
- Manage vendor relations including carriers, equipment, materials, facility, etc.

#### ASSISTANT GENERAL MANAGER / REGIONAL SALES MANAGER

Coughlin Printing Group

AGM 1/2013 - 9/2014

RSM 1/2011 - 1/2013

At Coughlin I managed a satellite branch while consulting with top tier clients which lead into improving operations and client experience company wide. I moved into the AGM position and worked closely with the GM to strategically plan and achieve company vision and goals.

Key responsibilities and accomplishments:

- Drove location revenue increase of 10% with a 3 year and counting positive trend.
- Increase profitability by streamlining purchase to fulfillment cycle.
- Create and maintain a culture of continuous improvement.
- Analyze operations, create, pilot, and refine procedure before company-wide roll out.